João Felipe Soares

Email: joaofsoares@yahoo.com

Ph. +353 83 300 8099

Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Fluent)

Career Summary

Work as a Java Developer with more than 12 years of experience in Information Technology. Certificated by Oracle on OCP Java SE 7 Programmer. Worked 1 year and half with Linux Support, certified by LPI with LPIC 2 certification, 7 years with JEE, JPA, EJB, RCP, WebLogic, PL/SQL on Oracle 11g and 12c, 1 year and half with Scala, Micro Services, Akka HTTP, Play 2, MySQL and 6 months working with C#. In his free time, he likes to study different technologies such as Haskell, C/C++ and Zig.

Education and Certifications

2023 Programming in C++: A Hands-on Introduction Specialization - Coursera - License: UU3RP9MZ57ZK

2023 Programming with Google Go - Coursera - License: YJXCAH87XC4X

2021 Business Intelligence, Big Data and Analytics - Data Science, Faculdade Anhanguera, São Paulo, Brazil

2018 Functional Programming in Scala Specialization - Coursera - License: WG68RE7AC4SK

2016 Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 7 Programmer - ORACLE - License: OC1363764

2016 Specialization in Architecture of Solutions in Technology, DeVry Metrocamp, Campinas São Paulo, Brazil.

2015 Bachelor in Computer Science, Faculdade Anhanguera, Rio Claro, São Paulo, Brazil

2010 Computer Technician, Senac São Paulo, Rio Claro, São Paulo, Brazil

Work History

Fidelity Investments. Feb 2024 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Post Trade

Building features in the backend and supporting applications as part of the Post Trade environment.

Technologies: Java 8, Java 17, Spring, Apache Camel, Apache Kafka, Jenkins, Datadog, AWS, Oracle Database.

HPE. Sep 2023 - Feb 2024

Cloud Engineer HPE Greenlake

Unified Support

Building backend features, to integrate different HPE services to provide to the customer an Unified Support experience. Allowing different users, from different sources interact with one single portal contemplating all customer's services (like support, cases, devices) integrating with AI (Coveo).

Technologies: GoLang, Kubernetes, Jenkins, NewRelic, AWS Canary.

Fidelity. Jun 2020 - April 2023

Senior Software Engineer

High Income Placement Service / Electronic Trading Fix Service

Building features in the backend, allowing traders to publish orders automatically to the market crossing ETL process ensuring security and quality for each order.

- Backend development
- Bug fix / Application improvements
- Documentation
- Jenkins pipelines
- Unit, Integration and Performance Tests

Technologies: Java 8, Spring, Kafka Spring, Apache Camel, Karate Gatling, Oracle Database, AWS, Jenkins.

Corporate Access Portal

Developing new features for the Salesforce platform using lighting components and backend. Including integration development using AWS Lambda.

- Salesforce
- Web Services
- AWS Lambda
- Unit Tests
- Product improvement
- Documentation
- Jenkins Pipelines
- Automation Tests

Technologies: Salesforce Apex, Java 8, Javascript, Jenkins, AWS Lambda (NodeJs, Python), Spring 5, JUnit, Cucumber, GIT, Maven, JFrog artifactory.

Airboxlab / Foobot. Dec 2019 - Jun 2020 (Luxembourg)

Senior Backend Developer

Foobot

- Java, Scala, Python Development
- AWS DevOps
- ETL
- Integration Tests
- Product improvement

Documentation

Technologies: Java 8, Scala, Python, MySQL, Jenkins, AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB), Spring 4, JUnit GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Red Hat Linux, Ubuntu Server.

Devoteam. Oct 2018 – Jun 2019 (Luxembourg)

Java/J2EE Developer

Société Générale Bank & Trust

- Java Development
- Front End Development
- PL/SQL Development (Oracle 12c)
- ETL
- Bug Fix
- Environment configuration
- Documentation

Technologies: Java 8, React JS, Oracle 12c, Spring 4, JUnit, GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Red Hat Linux.

Ibrowse Consultoria e Informática. Aug 2017 - May 2019 (Remote)

Java/J2EE Consultant

Java consultant on demand for several projects linked to the public sector.

- Java Development
- Bug Fix
- Unit Tests
- Documentation

Technologies: Java 8, Spring 4, JUnit, Maven, GIT.

e-Spatial Solutions. Dec 2017 - Sep 2018 (Ireland)

Java/J2EE Developer

Department of Agriculture, Food and the Marine - LPIS

Developing software customization using iSmart products for the Department of Agriculture, Food and the Marine of Ireland. LPIS is the Department of Agriculture's spatial database that underpins area-based payments to Irish farmers.

- Java Development
- PL/SQL Development (Oracle Spatial)
- GIS (iSmart)
- Environment configuration
- Documentation

Technologies: Java 8, Oracle 12c, Spring 4, JUnit, SVN, Maven, GIS (iSmart), Bamboo, SonarQube.

Suntech do Brasil. Dec 2016 - Aug 2017 (Brazil)

Java/J2EE Developer

- Linux installation, configuration and maintenance
- Deploy process
- MySQL maintenance
- Access Control creation
- Authentication Encryption Library (Scala 2.12 Library)
- Integration with other solutions of the company by services (Scala, Akka HTTP, Java 8, REST and SOAP)

Multi Configurator Tracker Suntech.

Developing software tools to configure trackers systems from Suntech.

- Migration system from VB to Java 8
- Creation of new features
- Bug Fix
- Web services development (Java 8, Spring, REST)
- Unit test development
- Documentation

Technologies: Java 8, JPA, Hibernate, SOAP, JUnit, MySQL, GIT, Maven, Scala (Play 2, Akka HTTP, SBT), GIT, Ubuntu Server, Serial Port Configuration.

Suntech Cockpit Project.

Developing software to asset management, forecast sales, logistic, general report and stock control.

- Manager meeting to create a new solution and road map
- Software available to Korean team
- Features development
- Bug Fix
- Unit test development
- Documentation

Technologies: React JS, Scala 2.12, Spray, Web Services, MySQL, GIT.

Suntech Billing Project.

Developing software to control and deliver the billing process. Libraries developed in Scala to improve the project performance and features.

- Manager meeting to create a new solution and road map
- Following company rules for each client
- Features development
- Bug Fix
- Unit test development
- Documentation

Technologies: React JS, Java 8, Spring, Web Services, MySQL, GIT.

Plus IT Consulting. Apr 2016 - Dec 2016 (Brazil)

Java/J2EE Developer

Canal Conecta Project Kroton Educação.

Developing software tools for education.

- Manager meeting to discuss new features and improvements
- Oracle database maintenance
- Oracle database support on migration version
- Deploy process
- Help support team
- Development of internal and external web services (Java 8, Spring, Scala, Spray)
- Development of encryption system to authentication (Scala Library)
- Unit test development
- Linux configuration and maintenance

Technologies: Java 8, JPA, Hibernate, JUnit, HTML 5, Angular JS, Less, Bootstrap, Web Services (Rest and SOAP), Oracle 11g and 12c, Tomcat, JBoss (Wildfly 8), RedHat Linux, Scala (SBT, Play 2), GIT, Maven, Spring, JAX-RS, Google Maps.

CGI Group. Nov 2015 - Apr 2016 (Brazil)

GIS Consultant

KPIs Project NeoEnergia

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Development of new features on client site
- Validation features and process on client site
- Oracle PL SQL development

Technologies: C#, Visual Studio 2010, ESRI, Oracle 11g, SVN.

Indra Company. Mar 2013 - Nov 2015 (Brazil)

Systems Analyst

Vivo Star Project

Developed software tools for telecommunications system.

- Features development
- Deploy on WebLogic and TomCat
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 7, PL/SQL, JPA, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSF, Oracle Weblogic, SVN/GIT.

InGRID Project

Developing software tools for energy electric systems using GIS.

- Support N3
- Implementation of new features

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

InNDM Project

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Finish project development
- Support implementation
- Meeting with functional team and managers to discuss Go Live process
- Deploy process on WebLogic
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

Comgás Project - Smallworld GIS

Developing software tools for gas distribution system using GE Smallworld.

- Customized Web tool used by GE Smallworld SIAS
- Documentation of features ordered by the client
- Oracle Database maintenance
- JBoss configuration
- Deploy process

Technologies: Java 7, J2EE, JSF, Smallworld, Magik, PL/SQL, JBOSS, MyEclipse, SVN.

ATOS. Sep 2012 - Mar 2013 (Brazil)

System Analyst

Developed software tools for CPFL Company using Magik. Smallworld GE Product.

- Development of Magik engine to extract VMDS information to Oracle Database
- · Work on database maintenance using PL SQL

Technologies: Magik, Smallworld Electric Office, SVN.

Indra Company. May 2011 - Sep 2012 (Brazil)

Trainee Programmer

InGRID Project.

Developing software tools for energy electric systems using GIS.

- Support N3
- Implementation of new features
- Participated in the Go Live period, fixing implementation bugs.

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

InNDM Project.

Developing software tools for energy electric system using GIS.

- Features implementation
- Meeting with functional team to discuss features
- Presentation environment creation
- Linux configuration and maintenance

- Deploy process on WebLogic
- Bug fix

Technologies: Java 6, JEE, Java RCP, PLSQL, EJB, JPA, GIS (IGEA), Oracle Weblogic, SVN.

SPQR Tecnologia da Informação. Feb 2010 - May 2011 (Brazil)

Support Analyst

Support in Linux systems for MicroCPD Company.

- Configuration of MicroCPD systems
- Remote support on applications services (Squid, Iptables, Samba, Apache)
- Installation of the product on client
- Shell Script maintenance and development
- Hardware maintenance

Technologies: CentOS Linux, Shell scripting.